Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee School of Information Studies Records, 1956-2014
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1956-2014, UWM Archival Collection 23; 20.4 cubic ft. (30 boxes) 106 digital text files (6.68 MB)
  - Program Entitlements and Proposals, 2001-2002 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Program Presentation
    - 1996 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - 2003 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Working Copy, 1994-1996 (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
  - Program Presentation to ALA Committee on Accreditation, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Programs and Speakers, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Promotional Materials
    - 1965-1986 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Bachelor of Science in Information Resources, 1998, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Proposal for the Establishment of a Center for Information Policy Research, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Proposed Curriculum Revision, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Protocol Summary, 2007 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Public Librarian Certification Mentoring Program, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Publications, 1984-1989, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Publications Committee, Minutes, 1967-1979 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Questionnaires, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - R.R. Bowker, 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 47-48)
  - Reaccreditation, Program Presentation Steering Committee Files, 1994-1996 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Recruitment Committee, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - "Reference Materials for Today: Suggested Materials for a Citizen's Library", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 50-51)
  - Religious Studies Committee, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Report to the Helen Bader Foundation, 1999-2004 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Research and Development Committee, 2002-2004 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Research and Graduate Program Committee, 2002-2003 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Resource Center
    - 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Committee, Minutes, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Resource Planning Documents for 1998-1999 and 1999-2000, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Retitling of Curricular Area, SOIS, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Revised Long-Range Plan, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Scholastic Standing and Appeals Committee
    - 1981-2002 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 2001 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Minutes and Correspondence, 1980-1999 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - School of Library Science
    - Mission, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Status, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Task Force, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Search and Screen Committee, 1970-1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Self Study
    - Process, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
    - Report
      - 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - 1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - 1988 (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - 1999 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - 1999 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Steering Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Subcommittee, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 12-15)
  - Senkevitch Communications, Miscellaneous, Office, 1998-1999 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - SLIS Advisory Council, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - SLIS to SOIS Name Change File, 1999-2001 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - SLIS Update, 1992-1997 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Special Events Committee, 1967-1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Standing Committee Annual Reports, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Status Report Notifications, Junior Faculty, 2009-2010 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Steering Committee
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Storyteller in Residence, Proposal, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Strategic Plan, 1996-2000 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Strategic Plan for the Year, 1998-2000 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Student and Alumni Affairs Committee, 1970-1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Student Organization
    - General Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Newsletter, 1972-1981 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
  - Sullivan-Spaights Advisory Board
    - 1992-1997 (Box 19, Folder 50-54)
    - 1997 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Surveys and Reports, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Sweetland Communications, Miscellaneous Office, 2002-2003 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Syllabi
    - 1999-2006, 8 folders
    - 1999-2001 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 29, Folder 16-20)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 29, Folder 21-26)
    - 2010 (Box 29, Folder 27-28)
    - 2010 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - 2011 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - 530-102, Intro to Bibliographic Control of Library Materials, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - 540-101, Using Information Sources and Services, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - 540-101, Information Literacy/Using Information Sources and Services, 1997-2001 (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - 540-110, Introduction to Information Science, 2000-2006 (Box 19, Folder 58)
    - 540-150, Introduction to Library Resources in the Information Superhighway (Internet), 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - 540-150, Introduction to Information Resources on the Internet, 1997-2006 (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - 540-210, Foundations of University Library Research, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - 540-210, Information Resources for Research/Foundations of University Library Research, 1997-2006 (Box 19, Folder 60)
    - 540-230, Organization of Knowledge, 1998-2004 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 540-250, Internet Communications and Information Transfer/Internet Planning and Implementation for Information Services, 2001-2003 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - 540-310, Human Factors in Information Seeking and Use, 2001-2005 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - 540-330, Electronic Information Retrieval Systems, 2000-2003 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - 540-340, Information Architecture II, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - 540-410, Database Information Retrieval Systems, 1999-2005 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 540-430, Multimedia Application Development, 2000-2002 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - 540-470, Introduction to Legal Bibliography, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - 540-470, Introduction to Legal Bibliography, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - 540-475, Legal Aspects of Information Products and Services, 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - 540-480, Books, Paper and their Preservation, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - 540-480, Books, Paper, and their Preservation, 1997-2006 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - 540-490, Senior Capstone, 1999-2004 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - 540-510, Introduction to Reference Services and Resources, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - 540-510, Introduction to Reference Services and Resources, 1997-2006 (Box 20, Folder 12-14)
    - 540-520, Managing Library Collections, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - 540-520, Managing Library Collections and Services, 1996-2006 (Box 20, Folder 15-16)
    - 540-530, Introduction to Bibliographic Control of Library Materials, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - 540-530, Introduction to Bibliographic Control of Materials, 1997-2002 (Box 20, Folder 17-19)
    - 540-531, Organization of Information, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - 540-540, Management of Libraries and Information Services, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - 540-540, Management of Library and Information Services, 1997-2002 (Box 20, Folder 21-24)
    - 540-550, Introduction to Information Science, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - 540-550, Introduction to Information Studies, 1999-2002 (Box 20, Folder 25-27)
    - 540-615, Information and Records Management, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - 540-615, Electronic Document and Records Management, 1996-2001 (Box 20, Folder 28-29)
    - 540-620, Ethics and the Information Society, 2001-2003 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - 540-632, Microcomputers for Information Resources Management, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - 540-632, Microcomputers for Information Resources Management, 1997-2002 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - 540-640, Information Marketing, 1999-2003 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - 540-648, Library Materials for Children, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - 540-648, Library Materials for Children, 1996-2002 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - 540-658, Library Materials for Young Adults, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - 540-658, Library Materials for Young Adults, 1995-2001 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - 540-670, Production and Utilization of Instructional Technology, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - 540-670, Production and Utilization of Instructional Technology, 1997-2002 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - 540-672, School Library Media Programs and Resources, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - 540-672, School Library Media Programs and Resources, 1995-1998 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - 540-680, A History of Books and Printing, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - 540-680, A History of Books and Printing, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - 540-681, Using Archives: The Values Sources in the Information Age, 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - 540-683, Cartographic Resources in Libraries, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - 540-691, One Credit Courses about Children's Literature, Folktales and Authors, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - 540-691, Bibliographic Instruction, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - 540-691, Book Repair and Binding, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - 540-691, Book Repair and Binding, 1999-2001 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - 540-691, Competitive Intelligence, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - 540-691, Computer-Based Training Using Toolbook, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - 540-691, Copyright for Educators, 2000-2001 (Box 20, Folder 44-45)
    - 540-691, Copyright Issues in Education, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - 540-691, Digital Libraries, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - 540-691, Electronic Documents and Records Management, 1997-2000 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - 540-691, Ethics and Information Society, 1997-1999 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - 540-691, Evaluation of Library Services, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - 540-691, Evaluation of Library Services, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - 540-691, Fundamentals of Budgeting Information Services, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - 540-691, Genealogy, In Search of Your Family, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - 540-691, Genealogy, Searching for Your Family (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - 540-691, History of Books and Printing, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - 540-691, Information Marketing, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - 540-691, Information Marketing, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - 540-691, Information Policy, 1998-2001 (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - 540-691, Information Storage and Retrieval, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - 540-691, Intellectual Freedom, A Continuing Problem in American Culture, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - 540-691, Internetworking with Windows NT, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - 540-691, Introduction to Information and Knowledge Management, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 57)
    - 540-691, Introduction to Westlaw, undated (Box 20, Folder 58)
    - 540-691, Law Library Administration, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - 540-691, Law Library Administration, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 59)
    - 540-691, Legal Issues for Library and Information Managers, 1997-2002 (Box 20, Folder 60)
    - 540-691, Legal Issues in Library and Information Science, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - 540-691, Library User Education, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 61)
    - 540-691, Location Based Information: the History, Development, Planning, and Design of Libraries, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 62)
    - 540-691, Managing an Information Infrastructure, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 63)
    - 540-691, Metadata, 1998-2001 (Box 20, Folder 64)
    - 540-691, Multicultural Children's Literature, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 65)
    - 540-691, PC Technology Support and Maintenance, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 66)
    - 540-691, Storytelling (Emphasis on Draw and Tell), 2001 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - 540-691, Storytelling for School Age Children, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 67)
    - 540-691, Technology Training and E-Learning, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 68)
    - 540-691, Various Syllabi for Children's Literature and Folktale Courses, 1997-2001 (Box 20, Folder 69)
    - 540-691, Windows NT Server 4.0 Planning and Management, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 70)
    - 540-710, Electronic Networking and Information Services, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - 540-710, Electronic Networking and Information Services, 1997-2003 (Box 20, Folder 71)
    - 540-715, Advanced Reference Services and Resources, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - 540-731, Advanced Cataloging and Classification, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - 540-731, Advanced Cataloging and Classification, 1999-2002 (Box 20, Folder 72)
    - 540-737, Serials Management, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - 540-742, Advanced Use of Microcomputers for Library and Information Management, 1997-2000 (Box 20, Folder 73)
    - 540-751, Library Services and Resources for Adults, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - 540-757, Library Services for Children and Young Adults, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - 540-757, Library Services for Children and Young Adults, 1997-2003 (Box 20, Folder 74)
    - 540-770, The Academic Library, 1997-2001 (Box 20, Folder 75)
    - 540-771, The Public Library, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - 540-771, The Public Library, 1997-2003 (Box 20, Folder 76)
    - 540-772, The Special Library and Information Center, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - 540-772, The Special Library and Information Center, 1997-2001 (Box 20, Folder 77)
    - 540-774, Online Information Retrieval, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - 540-774, Online Information Retrieval, 1997-2002 (Box 20, Folder 78)
    - 540-775, Modern Archives Administration, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - 540-775, Modern Archives Administration, 1996-1999 (Box 20, Folder 79)
    - 540-777, Seminar in Modern Archives Administration, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - 540-777, Seminar in Modern Archives Administration, 1997-1999 (Box 20, Folder 80)
    - 540-781, Library and Automation, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - 540-781, Library Automation, 1998-2003 (Box 20, Folder 81)
    - 540-782, Information Systems, Analysis and Design, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - 540-782, Information Systems, Analysis and Design, 1999-2001 (Box 20, Folder 82)
    - 540-784, Advanced Topics in Information Retrieval, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 83)
    - 540-784, Advanced Topics in Information Retrieval, Health Sciences, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - 540-790, Fieldwork in Archives and Manuscripts, 1997-2000 (Box 20, Folder 84)
    - 540-791, Topics in Indexing and Abstracting, Back of the Book Indexing, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - 540-801, Seminar in Education and Media Technology, 1999-2003 (Box 20, Folder 85)
    - 540-811, Information Sources and Services in Social Sciences, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - 540-812, Information Sources and Services in the Humanities, 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 87)
    - 540-813, Information Sources and Services in Science and Technology, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 60)
    - 540-813, Information Sources and Services in Science and Technology, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 88)
    - 540-814, Government Information Sources and Services, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 61)
    - 540-814, Government Information Sources and Services, 1997-2003 (Box 20, Folder 89)
    - 540-816, Competitive Intelligence and Business Information Resources, 1998-2003 (Box 20, Folder 90)
    - 540-816, Information Sources and Services in Business, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 62-63)
    - 540-817, Information Sources and Services in the Health Sciences, 1998-2001 (Box 20, Folder 91)
    - 540-820, Seminar in Intellectual Freedom, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 92)
    - 540-825, Legal Issues for Library and Information Managers, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 93)
    - 540-840, Seminar in International and Multicultural Information Sources, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 94)
    - 540-876, Seminar in Library Administration, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 64)
    - 540-890, Research Methods in Library and Information Science, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 65)
    - 540-891, Advanced Topics in Library and Information Science, Hypermedia, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 66)
    - 540-891, Appraising and Selecting Archival Records, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 95)
    - 540-891, Automated Archival Techniques, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 69)
    - 540-891, Database Systems for Information Management, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 67)
    - 540-891, Information Management in Higher Education and the Role of the Academic Library, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 68)
    - 540-891, Multimedia and Hypermedia, 1997-1999 (Box 20, Folder 96)
  - Teaching Evaluations, Summaries, 1972-1982 (Box 7)
  - Ten-Year Review for Graduate School, 1989, 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Testimonials, 1987-2002 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Thesis Option, 1999-2002 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Travel Committee, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Undergraduate Certificates in Library and Information Science (now discontinued), 2003 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Undergraduate Program Committee, 2002-2004 (Box 20, Folder 97)
  - Undergraduate Program Implementation Committee, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Undergraduate Student Academic Misconduct Committee, 2004-2005 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Update Newsletter
    - 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1998 (Box 20, Folder 99)
  - Urban Education PhD Committee, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 98)
  - Utilization Analysis: Affirmative Action, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - UWM Alumni Association Honors Committee, 2006-2007 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Vevier, Charles, 1963-1971 (Box 6, Folder 12-14)
  - Visit by Egyptian University President, Miscellaneous Communications, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 100)
  - Visit by Senegal University President, Miscellaneous Communications, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 101)
  - Wallace McClain Cheatham, Honorary Doctorate, 2001-2002 (Box 20, Folder 102)
  - Wisconsin International Trade Survey of SLIS, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "Wisconsin's Own Library" Advisory Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - WISE Meetings and General Information, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Yale University Libraries, Customized MLIS, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 103)
- Milwaukee Teachers Education Center Records, 2003-2004, Accession 2008-072; 26 digital files (1 MB); Materials related to a School Library Media Certification offered by SOIS in conjunction with the Milwaukee Teachers Education Center (MTEC), which ran between 2001-2004. Accession includes memoranda related to the establishment of the program.
- Additions, 1982-2012, Accession 2011-041; 3.2 cubic ft. (5 boxes); Additions of subject, accreditation, and search and screen files, dating from 1982 to 2009. Records include course syllabi from 2001-2009, minutes of various SOIS and SOIS-related committees, and presentations for SOIS' ALA reaccreditation visit in 2003. The largest part of the collection is comprised of photograph albums from 1982-2012. Photos include portraits, candid photos of faculty and staff, and specific events; many photos in the albums are identified with post-it notes or by SOIS staff annotations on the reverse.
- Subject, Personnel, and Accreditation Files, 1990-2003, Accession 2013-024; 2,090 digital files (173 MB); Additions of subject, personnel, and accreditation files, dating from 1990 to 2003. Paper files include copies of faculty committee minutes and agendas, reports, organization charts, correspondence files for events and programs sponsored by SOIS (including the Ted Samore Lecture and awards ceremonies), course syllabi, and promotional material for SOIS. The electronic files contain similar materials, but for more recent timeframes than represented in the paper files, suggesting the school's move to electronic documents as official records; most of the folders are meeting minutes and attachments, but also included are course syllabi and a copy of the website created for SOIS' ALA reaccreditation process in 2003.